嘿，你们好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列，那么今天有了些不同的东西
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my game engine series, so today we've got something a little bit different
首先，我想让你们看上一期视频，如果还没有看过的话
first of all, I want you guys to watch the previous episode, if you haven't already
现在我们已经完成了所有我想做的ImGui内容
that's us finishing up all of the ImGui stuff that I wanted to actually do, now that we've done that
我们将继续讨论一个非常大的新主题，就是渲染器，首先，让我们谈谈本期的不同之处
we're going to move on to a very big new topic called renderer now, first of all, let's talk about what's different in this episode
我的电脑刚刚完全坏了，好像根本不能运行，真是太棒了
my computer has just completely broken himself, like just will not work at all, which is all great
如果我有足够的时间，我可能会修好它，但不幸的是我没有时间
and I could probably fix it, if I had enough time, but unfortunately I don't have time
因为目前，我在EA的寒霜引擎全职工作，我也在装修我的公寓
because at the moment, I'm working full time of course at EA on Frostbite, I'm also renovating my apartment
我大约一个月后就要结婚了，所以我要做很多婚礼准备，我的生活非常忙碌
I'm also getting married in about a month, so I have to do a lot of wedding preparation, and my life is just completely hectic
但我今天还是很想给你们拍一期视频，所以我想，你们知道的，今天我们谈谈
but I still really wanted to make a video for you guys, today, so I thought, you know, what let's just talk about stuff today
因为我们将要深入研究的整个渲染器主题非常复杂
because this whole renderer topic that we're about to dive into is so incredibly complicated
如果我想想我以前写过多少次渲染器
and just just enormous that you just really cannot plan enough, and if I think about how many times I've written a renderer before
我以前写过多少次渲染器接口抽象，不管我写了多少次，50年以后
and how many times I've written renderer api abstractions before, doesn't matter how many times I do this, I'm gonna be 50 years old
我还是会用另一种方式来写，因为它只是，它是难以置信的，就像它是疯狂的，多么复杂
and I'm still gonna be writing them a different way, because it's just, it's just incredible, like it's just crazy, how just complicated
还有多少事情需要知道，而我仍然不知道我在做什么
and how much stuff there is to actually know, and I still don't really know what I'm doing
所以，因为就像一个节拍被打破了一样，我真的什么都做不了，所以我选择了字体平移纸
so because like a beat is broken, and I can't really do anything of it, I've gone font pan paper
我们将讨论未来几周我们将要做的很多事情
and we're actually going to talk about a lot of what we're going to do in the coming weeks
因为我们现在在Hazel中要做的是，对吧，基本上是一个渲染器
because what we're going to do now in Hazel is, right, a renderer basically
好吧，那么那意味着我们今天要谈什么
okay, so what does that mean we're gonna talk today
我们将讨论那到底意味着什么，下周，我想做的实际上是把
we're gonna talk about what that means exactly, next week, what I want to do is actually put together probably
比如一个带有图表的PPT，像接口结构和所有内容
like a powerpoint presentation with like diagrams, and like the structure of the api and everything
我们正在以一种更正式的形式制作这段视频，对吧，现在实际上正在为每个人同时直播
we're doing in more of a formal kind of format this video, right, now is actually going live for everyone at the same time
所以赞助商们没有提前收到这段视频，只是因为我没有电脑
so patrons aren't getting this video early, just because of the fact that I've had no computer
我可能要在我的笔记本上编辑这个，太糟糕了，不管怎么说，那只是一方面
and I'm probably gonna have to edit this on my laptop, which is gonna be terrible, anyway, that a side
每个人都在同一时间得到这个，这很酷，因为我可以立即得到你们的反馈，那将非常好
everyone's getting this at the same time, which is cool, because I can get your feedback immediately, and that's gonna be quite good
因为下周我要做的是录制一段视频，在那里我会谈论整个事情的设计，对吧
because next week what I want to actually do is record a video, where I actually talk about the design of this whole thing, right
那会使用到PPT，因为我无法说服自己
and that's going to be like with a powerpoint kind of presentation, because there's no way I can just talk myself into this
这将是太多的信息，如果不画出来的话，很难想象
it's just going to be too much information, and it's going to be very hard to kind of visualize, if it's not drawn
就像给你们的实际图表一样，那就是下周要发生的事情，但今天我们只想谈谈这个
like like as an actual diagram for you guys, so that's what's gonna happen next week, but today we're just gonna talk about this
我只想告诉你们我的经验，这是渲染器的一般情况，并谈谈这对Hazel意味着什么
I'm just gonna give you my experience, which is renderer in general, and talk about what this means for Hazel
就像我们要谈谈，好吧，那么第一步，我在这里列出的第一件事
and like just we're just gonna talk, okay, so step one, and the first thing that I have on my list here
只是这是一个非常困难和复杂的话题，我们确定我们定义了这个话题实际上是什么
is just that it's a really hard and complex topic, we sure we define what the topic actually is
那么渲染器，渲染器涉及什么，我们在游戏引擎中需要什么
so renderer, what does renderer involve, what do we needed in a game engine
你们知道，它的目的是什么，为什么它在Hazel里，它做什么，好了
you know, what what is its purpose, why is it in Hazel, what does it do, okay
所以渲染器基本上是指我们在屏幕上绘制图形的能力，那通常意味着
so renderer refers to basically our ability to draw graphics on the screen, now what that means usually is
嘿，比如这个3D模型，我想绘制，我有这个世界，我想绘制
well hey, I have like this 3D model, I want to draw, I have this world, I want to draw
我有我构建的整个场景，我想实时渲染
I have this whole scene that I've built up, I want to render this in a in a real time fashion
那就是你们知道的足够快的实时性，所以可能每秒60帧，也就是每帧16.7毫秒
that is you know fast enough to actually be real time, so probably 60 frames per second, which is 16.7 milliseconds per frame
我希望它是交互式的，那意味着在输入和实际之间必须有相当低的延迟
and I want it to be interactive, which means that there has to be fairly low latency between input and actual
你们知道，如果执行某些操作并以某种方式影响渲染器，则渲染器本质上就是那样的
you know, if doing something and affecting the renderer in some way, that is essentially what renderer is
现在，为什么它如此复杂，我们实现渲染器的方式如此快速
now why is it so complicated, well, the way that we achieve renderer that is fast
它能够产生高保真的图形，这也是完全的，看，我一点都不专业
and that is capable of producing high fidelity graphics, which again is completely, see, I'm not professional at all
我们生产高保真度的东西的方式，对吧，这也是一个对每个人都有吸引力的术语，对吧
the way that we produce something that is high fidelity, right, which is again a term that like it to each their own, right
就像高分辨率对你们来说就是高保真图像，对吧
like what is high resolution was what's high fidelity graphics to you, right
你们知道，你们今天看到的很多可能都是一些由大公司发布的新游戏
a lot of what you see today is maybe some of the like new games, that are being released by huge companies, you know
你们看，我甚至可能在这里玩其中的一些，我不知道我是否能在版权方面
you see, like I might even play some of them here, I don't know if I can copyright wise
但是你们知道像《战场5》中新的光线追踪之类的东西
but you know stuff like the new ray tracing stuff in battlefield 5
你们知道你们已经有了所有这些即将面世的高保真图形
you know you've got all of these kind of high fidelity graphics that are coming out
我们通常认为它们是高保真的，因为它们接近真实照片
and we perceive them as high fidelity usually, because they're close to being photorealistic
这意味着渲染器技术实际上能够产生一些东西
which means that that renderer technology is actually capable of somewhat producing something
那看起来像是电影或实时照片，对吧，人们经常把它与现实世界的运行方式进行比较
that looks like a movie or a photograph in real time, right, and people compare it to how the real world works a lot
还有这些东西，比如基于物理的渲染器，实际上是基于曲面物理属性的渲染器
and you have these things, like physically based renderer, which is actually renderer based on physical properties of surfaces
就像光和光子是如何运行的，那是我们的追求
and like how light works and photons and all that kind of stuff, and that's kind of our pursuit
像我们一样，我们也在寻求一种实时渲染照片级真实感图形的方法，因为我们可以
our, like us actually pursuing a way to render photorealistic graphics in real time, because we can
我们或多或少可以渲染照片级真实感图形，对吧，但实时渲染确实很有挑战性
we can more or less render photorealistic graphics, right, but doing it in real time is really really challenging
人们之间有一种巨大的事情，显然想要实时做到那个
and there's like a huge, like huge, huge like thing going on with with people, obviously trying to achieve that in real time
但那还不是很好，当然这种光线追踪
but that's still kind of not really quite there yet, and certainly this kind of ray tracing
硬件以类似rtx的形式出现，例如在任何视频上
hardware is coming out in the form of like rtx for example on it on any video
那绝对像是步入了正确的方向，因为每个人都知道那个
that stuff is definitely like stepping into the right direction, because everyone knows that
光线跟踪就是，有多少离线渲染器，所以非实时渲染器
ray tracing is how you, how a lot of offline renderers, so non real time renderers
那么就是人们用来制作电影之类的渲染器
so renderers that people use for like movies and stuff like that
他们是如何通过光线跟踪类渲染器来实现照片真实感的
how they're able to achieve photorealism like quite unquote, right, is by using ray tracing kind of renderers
但无论如何，在这里超越我自己，这是非常复杂的，因为除了做所有那些
but anyway, getting ahead of myself here, it's very complicated, because apart from doing all of that
我们实际实现高性能的方式
the way that we actually achieve that high performance, or performance that is at the level
我们可以实时完成这些工作，同时仍能获得高保真的外观
where it's possible for us to do this stuff in real time, and still achieve a high fidelity look
我们需要使用GPU，它是图形处理单元，是一个专用的硬件
we need to use something called the GPU, which is the graphics processing unit, it's a dedicated piece of hardware
它存在于大多数计算机中，有时它集成到我们的CPU中，有各种不同的体系结构
that resides in most computers, sometimes it's integrated into our CPU, there are various architectures
比如这个硬件实际上是如何设置的，但最终它是一个专用芯片
for how this hardware is actually set up, but ultimately, it is a dedicated chip
它位于我们的计算机或我们正在使用的任何设备上
that is on our computer or our whatever device we're using
能够执行某些非常常见的数学运算或算法，例如
that is capable of performing or executing certain mathematical operations or algorithms, that are very common, for common
就像最终的渲染器任务或常见的图形处理任务一样，所以我们对图形所做的很多事情是
like renderer tasks eventually or common graphics processing tasks, so a lot of what we have to do with graphics is
在屏幕上显示大量像素，如果我们有全高清显示器，那个大约是200万像素
display a large number of pixels on the screen, if we have a full hd display, that's about 2 million pixels
我们通常需要一种方法来确定每个像素的颜色，这与其他像素无关
we need a way to determine the color for each pixel usually, this is independent of every other pixel
所以有可能并行地做这些事情，对吧，这是GPU通常非常擅长的事情
so it's possible to do that stuff in parallel, right, that is something that a GPU is usually quite good at
好了，其他的事情，就像你们知道的，我们处理很多四维向量，我们处理很多四乘四矩阵
okay, other things, like you know, we deal a lot with four component vectors, we deal a lot with four by four matrices
我们对GPU上的操作进行了硬件优化，这就是为什么它比在CPU上做这类事情更快的原因
we have hardware optimizations for operations like that on the GPU, which is why it's faster than doing these kinds of things on the CPU
所以并行处理和许多具体的数学运算就是它关键
so parallel processing and a lot of specific maths operations is the gist of it
显然，我们有特定的光线跟踪过程和其他类型的架构，它们可能有很多东西
obviously we have specific like ray tracing processes and other kind of architectures that may have a lot of things
但那只是为了让它保持基本，这是因为
but that's kind of just to dumb it down to keep it basic, it's because of that
是因为我们想在GPU上使用渲染器图形的数学运算速度更快，因为有专门的硬件
is because the math that we kind of want to use for renderer graphics is faster to do on the GPU, because of dedicated hardware for that
然后我们基本上有一个巨大的并行操作
and then also we have a large like huge paralyzation essentially
那让我们可以同时做很多操作，就像并行一样，好吧
that lets us do a lot of operations in just at the same time essentially like in parallel, okay
所以为了与这个GPU交互，我们必须使用一个叫做渲染接口的东西
so to interface with this GPU, we have to use something called a rendering api
现在我确实有一个OpenGL系列，你们可以去看看
now I do have an OpenGL series, which you can check out
但我确实意识到，随着时间的推移，OpenGL变得越来越少，我的意思是看着我自己
but I do realize as time goes on OpenGL is becoming less and less like a thing, and I mean look me personally
比如，如果你们问我个人，在高性能引擎中会使用什么
like if you ask me personally, what is yan chernikov, what is thecherno, going to use in his high performance engine
它会是OpenGL吗？当然不是，如果你们想成为最前沿的人，我不推荐使用OpenGL
is it gonna be OpenGL, of course not, OpenGL is not something that I can recommend using, if you're going for bleeding edge, cutting like edge
我不知道，我想在2009年用最好的图形渲染引擎完成最好的游戏
I don't know I want to make the best game end of the best graphics rendering engine in 2009
当然不是，你们不想用OpenGL
of course not, you don't want to OpenGL
如果你们完全处于顶端，你们可能想要Vulcan和DirectX12，对吧
you probably if you're absolutely at the top edge, you want probably the Vulcan DirectX12, right
我们不是一个大型游戏工作室或大型渲染引擎
we are not a huge game studio or a huge rendering powerhouse
它能够以某种方式立即实现Vulcan或DirectX 12渲染器
that is capable of implementing a Vulcan or a DirectX 12 renderer immediately in a way
那也可以教给你们所有人，因为Vulcan和DirectX12，特别是对Vulcan的研究是极其复杂的
that can also teach it to all of you guys, because Vulcan and DirectX12,  specifically looking at Vulcan bow is extremely complicated
首先你们并没有好好看看Vulcan，我，比如我，并没有人能给我确切的解释
first of you have not taken a good look at Vulcan, I like I am, there is no one to me cable of explaining exactly
Vulcan交换链实际上是如何运行的，以及OpenGL代码如何运行的，对吧，我可能会写
how like the Vulcan swap chain actually works, and how like OpenGL code, right, I can I can write you probably
OpenGL内存中基于物理的渲染器，与所有接口命令一样，一切正常
a physically based renderer from memory in OpenGL, like all api commands everything just correct
好吧，我可以那样做，因为它很简单，我可能无法在Vulcan为你们绘制一个三角形
right, I can do that, because it's simple Vulcan, I probably wouldn't be able to draw a triangle for you in Vulcan
在我的脑海里，不可能，不，我肯定不能，对吧，我曾用过Vulcan
off the top of my head, no way, no, I definitely wouldn't be able to, right, and I've worked with Vulcan
实际上，在它发布之前，我确实有很多使用Vulcan的经验，但我不能实现那个
since before it was released actually, so I do have quite a bit of Vulcan experience, and yet I'm not able to do that
因为这里非常复杂，比如需要1500行代码或其他东西来渲染一个三角形
because it's incredibly complicated here, like 1500 lines of code or something to render a triangle
那就是为什么我在一开始特别选择OpenGL作为渲染接口的原因
so that's why I've specifically gone with OpenGL as a rendering api in the beginning
为什么，是因为它是最好的选择吗？显然不是
why is it, is it because it's the best choice obviously not
但问题是，我不能花几百个视频建立一个Vulcan交换链来向你们展示这个
but the thing is, I can't spend hundred videos setting up a Vulcan swap chain to show you guys this
因为那会失去很多观众，那不会有意思，好吧，不是我们需要的东西
because that's gonna lose a lot of viewers, and that's not gonna be interesting, okay, and it's not something that we need
为什么呢，因为我可能更愿意让Hazel达到这样的程度，在那里可以渲染3D的PBD场景
why, because I might rather get Hazel to the point, where I can render like a pbr scene in 3d
然后就像，嘿，你们知道吗，也许现在将实现Vulcan
and then be like, hey, you know what, maybe now will implement Vulcan
因为我们已经到了关键时候，可能有必要
because we're getting to the point, where it might be necessary
所以你们必须从这种角度来看，很多人问我，如果我构建Hazel的方式
so you have to look at it from this kind of point of view, a lot of people asked me, if the way that I'm building Hazel
是我将如何构建我的引擎，或者如果我做出了所有正确的决定，我将做出正确的决定
is how I would build my engine, or if I'm making all the right decisions, I'm making the right decisions
考虑到这是YouTube上的一个视频系列，我想说得非常清楚，实际上非常像这期视频
considering it's a video series on YouTube, I want to make that absolutely clear, actually quite like this video
我只是在咆哮，只是在解释一切是如何运行的，这很好，因为我读到了很多评论
I'm just ranting a lot, I'm venting I'm just explaining how everything's working, which is good, because there's so many comments I've read
还有很多我想说的话，但我无论如何都不能
and so many things I wanted to say, but I can't, anyway
嗯，所以说，那就是为什么我们展示了一个OpenGL
huh so that being said, that's why we've kind of shows an OpenGL
因为它允许我们访问显卡并实际使用它，但它是实现那个最简单的接口
because it allows us to tap into our graphics card, and actually use it, but it's the most simple api for doing that
OpenGL非常简单，就抽象的层次或程度而言，它就比如10个难度，这是对的
OpenGL is extremely simple, it's like 10 out of 10 in terms of how high level or over an abstraction, it is right
而Vulcan可能是1，DirectX12可能在3，而DirecX11和Metal可能是5或6左右
whereas Vulcan might be like a one, DirectX 12 might be like a three, DirectX 11 and like Metal might be around a five or six
而Vulcan就像你们所知道的一样在一个极端，OpenGL在另一个极端，也很有趣
whereas Vulcan is like you know on one extreme, and OpenGL is on the other upstream, which is quite interesting as well to just look at
好吧，这里的情况变得更复杂了，所以好吧，你们选择个渲染接口，允许使用显卡
okay, so here's where it gets even more complicated though, so okay, you pick a rendering api, which lets you use the graphics card
这就是要执行渲染的操作，对吧，那在某种程度上来说就是我们的任务
which is what you want to do to perform rendering, right, that's our task in a way
但问题是一个显卡接口是不够的，现在OpenGL至少在过去发生过，现在更多
but the problem is one graphics api is not enough, now OpenGL is something that happens to at least in the past, now more
所以它越来越被遗弃，越来越不受欢迎，就像被踢出了一样，随便你们怎么说
so it's getting more deprecated, and it's getting more or less kind of removed, like channeled out, whatever you want to call it
所以现在有点不同了，但在过去OpenGL非常好，从某种意义上说，它可以处理所有的事情
so it's a little bit different now, but in the past OpenGL was extremely good, in the sense that it just worked on everything
几乎和Java一样，实际上我可以将其与Java进行比较，因为Java在任何地方都可以运行星号
was almost like Java, actually I might compare it to java, because java worked asterisk everywhere
但这是最垃圾的，对吧，我想说OpenGL就像是绝对的垃圾或类似的东西
but it was most the garbage, right, I want to say OpenGL is like just absolute garbage or anything like that
实际上，我非常喜欢OpenGL，因为它非常简单，非常漂亮，非常温暖
I actually quite like OpenGL in the sense that it's just so simple, it's so nice and warm
在其他最终渲染接口上花了一段时间后，又回到了OpenGL，像这样真是太疯狂了
and inviting to come back to OpenGL after spending some time in other redener apis and being like this is insane
在某种程度上回到OpenGL是很好的，尽管我仍然认为接口并不令人惊奇
it's nice to come back to OpenGL in a way, even though I still think the api is not amazing
但回到OpenGL并不是很令人惊奇还是很好的
it's still nice to come back to OpenGL and not amazing
顺便说一句，我把它放得很轻，但不管怎样，回到OpenGL总是很好的
I'm putting it lightly by the way, but anyway coming back OpenGL is always nice
因为它非常简单，对吧，非常简单
because it's so simple, right, it's incredibly simple
现在的问题是，我甚至不记得我要说的是什么，但问题是当你们有了真正的
now the thing is though, and I don't even remember where I was going with this, but the thing is when you have something really
当你们回到设计所有这些渲染接口时，你们会考虑实际需要什么
when you go back to designing all these rendering apis, and you think about what you actually need
这就成了一个问题，我基本上是在什么平台上发布的，对吧
it becomes a problem of what platforms essentially am I kind of shipping on, right
所以，在完全忘记要说什么之前，当刚才谈论这个时，把它往回点，我说的是OpenGL
so to drag this back a little bit as I was just talking earlier, before I completely forgot where I was going, I was saying that OpenGL
在当时，它有点像java，因为它在任何地方都能运行
back in the day, it was kind of just like java in the sense that it just worked everywhere
对吧，我是说Windows Mac Linux Android IOS，都运行了，它们都能够运行OpenGL
right, I mean Windows Mac Linux Android IOS, they all ran, they were all capable of running OpenGL
然而现在如果看看发生了什么，就像你们知道的一样，并不是说在Windows上不是绝对的好
whereas now if you take a look at what's happening, we're like you know, not saying Windows wasn't absolutely great with it
但就像Android IOS一样，你们知道Mac Linux，它们都是在它上面运行的，对吧
but like Android IOS, you know Mac Linux, they all kind of ran on it, right
但是现在如果你们看看接口的状态，在给定的平台上，什么是最好的渲染接口
but now if you look at the state of apis, what is the best api render on a given platform
对于Windows，是DirectX 11或DirectX 12
for Windows, it's DirectX 11 or DirectX 12
对于Mac，它是Metal，对于IOS，它是Metal，对于Linux，它是Vulcan
for Mac, it's Metal, and for IOS it's Metal, for Linux, it's Vulcan
对于Android，它是Vulcan，可能是GL，对吧，也就是Glass
for Android, it's Vulcan, maybe gl gls right glass
但那可能是针对老式设备的，主要是Vulcan，对吧
but that's for probably older devices mostly Vulcan, right
我漏了什么吗，对于Xbox，通常是DirectX 12
did I miss anything, for Xbox, it's DirectX 12 usually
对于ps4，漏掉的是索尼自己的专有接口，我总是忘记它的名字，因为我不太经常用它
and for ps4 which I'm missing out on is sony's own proprietary api, which I always forget the name of, because I don't deal with it too often
然后就像任天堂交换机一样，老实说，我想它也可能是Vulcan，但我不是百分之百确定
and then for like the Nintendo Switch, I think it might be Vulcan as well, to be honest, but I'm not 100% sure
不管怎样，对于那些平台，你们可以看到OpenGL是不存在的
anyway for those kind of platforms, you can see that OpenGL is not existent
对吧，我选择OpenGL了吗，没有
right, do I pick OpenGL, well no
也许在旧的Android设备上，这可能是你们选择OpenGL的唯一原因
maybe on older Android devices, it's pretty much maybe the only reason you pick OpenGL
对吧，仍然可以在Windows上渲染OpenGL
right, you can still render OpenGL on Windows
但是，如果你们真的想在Windows上渲染，那么应该使用DirectX，不是吗
but is it preferred, no, you should be using DirectX, if you're serious about rendering on Windows
就那么简单，我要说的是，你们需要提升，不能只使用一个渲染接口
it's as simple as that, where I'm going with this is that you need to ascent, you can't get away with using with using one rendering api
那就是渲染变得非常复杂的原因，其中一个原因是如果渲染变得复杂
and that's why rendering becomes really complicated, well one of the reasons is if it becomes complicated
因为你们需要做一些事情，所以需要设计一个接口抽象
because you need to do something, you design an api abstraction
它将所有实际的渲染接口类调用隐藏在你们自己的抽象背后
which hides away all of the actual render api like calls behind your own abstraction
因此，理想情况下，在这种情况下，Hazel有自己的接口，它有自己的渲染接口
so that ideally you basically are in this case, Hazel has its own api, it has its own rendering api
然后渲染接口可以使用DirectX12，可以使用DirectX11，可以使用Vulcan，使用OpenGL
and then that rendering api could be using either DirectX 12, could be using DirectX 11, could be using Vulcan, could be using OpenGL
可以使用Metal，对吧，它可以同时使用任何渲染接口，但你们告诉Hazel
could be using Metal whatever, right, it could be using any rendering api at once, but you tell Hazel
我想上传一个充满数据的顶点缓冲区，它会实现那个，它是如何使用哪个接口实现的
I want to upload a vertex buffer full of data, it does that, how it does that using which api
那是我们不想担心的实现细节，我们有一个抽象层，一个可以告诉Hazel的接口
that's implementation details that we don't want to worry about, we have this abstraction layer, an api where we can generically tell Hazel
上传这个顶点缓冲区，上传这个纹理数据，你们知道的，我想渲染
upload this vertex buffer, upload this texture data, you know I want to render
你们知道从这个索引缓冲区中有三个索引
you know from this index buffer three indices
用这个顶点缓冲区，用这个材质，用这个着色器
and with this vertex buffer, with this material, with this shader
有了这个拓扑结构，我不知道，只有100万个不同的细节，对吧，但关键是我们告诉Hazel
with this you know topology, I don't know, just 1 million different details, right, but the point is we tell Hazel
我们想让Hazel知道，好吧，我们在Windows上运行
we want that Hazel figures out, okay well, we're running on Windows
目前正在使用DirectX 11，因为那是我们选择的
and we're currently using DirectX 11, because that's what we've selected
当然我会用它，或者我们现在在Mac上运行，所以我会用Metal，我想成为你们，明白了吧
definitely I'm gonna use that, or we're currently running on a Mac, so I'm gonna use Metal, I wanted to be you kind of get the point, right
我们有这个抽象层，所以我们的应用程序代码不会根据其运行的内容而改变
we have this abstraction layer, so that our application code doesn't change based on what it's running on
它将在我们实际设置的平台和配置上使用最佳的渲染接口
and it will be using the optimal rendering api on the platform and configuration that we've actually set up
那是非常困难的，好吧，那是非常困难的，因为你们需要做的是在某处画一条线
that's extremely difficult to do, okay, that's extremely difficult to do, because what you need to do is draw a line somewhere
这就是我的接口看起来的样子，那真的很难，因为图形处理得越多，就越深入
and see this is what my api looks like, that's really difficult, because the more you go on with graphics, and the further you get
而且，你们开始实现的技术越先进，你们可能需要更多的控制
and the more advanced techniques you start implementing, you may need more control
拖动整个接口的界限是一项巨大而昂贵的任务
dragging the whole api line is a huge expensive task to do
如果你们不清楚我所说的接口是什么意思，那就是抽象的地方，换句话说
case you guys aren't clear by what I mean by api line, it's where you draw the abstraction, so in other words
很高的级别可能是在这里绘制三角形，很低的级别可能比如解锁Vulcan信号灯，对吧
where really high level might be drawed triangle at this location and really low level might be like, unlock my Vulcan semaphore, right
那可能是两个极端，或者你们知道的
that's kind of maybe the two extremes, or like you know
就像在释放内存或其他类似的，你们在哪里划界非常重要，对吧
like on releases memory fence or whatever like it it, where you draw the line is really important, right
通常我倾向于从概念上思考，所以它们只是在这期视频中掉了两次
now usually what I tend to do is I like to think of it conceptually, so things like, so they just do that again twice in one video man
不管怎样，我们这样做，在一个点上画一条线，我喜欢可能想说，我想要一个顶点缓冲区
anyway, so we do it, we kind of draw the line at a point, where I like, I might want to say, I want a vertex buffer
我想要一个索引缓冲区，一个纹理，一个着色器，我想要，你们知道，着色器上有什么接口
I want an index buffer, I want a texture, I want a shader, I want to, you know, what api exists on the shader
我想找出关于我的统一变量信息作为我的属性，我想能够设置统一变量缓冲区
well I want to find out information about my uniform as my attributes, I want to be able to set up uniform buffers
我希望能够上传统一缓冲区的部分，我可能希望检索有关属性的信息
I want to be able to kind of upload sections of uniform buffers, I might want to retrieve information about attributes
我可能想检索某些其他信息，对吧，你们可能想做很多事情
I might want to retrieve certain other information, right, there's a lot of things that you might want to do
我可能想获得附加到该着色器的所有资源，例如不同的纹理，以及比如采样
I might want to get all the resources attached to that shader, such as different textures, and like samples
也许它像有多少纹理，多少输出，我必须打开它们到帧缓冲区，你们必须有一种接口
maybe it like how many textures, how many outpluses do I have to open them up to frame buffers, you have to you have to kind of have an api
那足够灵活，允许你们实现所有这些渲染器技术，但也可以抽象掉所有这些接口
that is flexible enough that allows you to implement all these renderer techniques, but also abstracts away all of these apis
但还有一个问题，这些接口的运行方式不同，对吧，这些接口的运行方式不同
but here's the other problem, these apis do not work the same way, right, these apis do not work the same way
OpenGL与Vulcan完全不同
OpenGL is completely different to Vulcan
对吧，我的意思是，在概念上，你们可以把它抽象出来，然后看到
right, I mean yes conceptually you can abstract it out and see
你们知道，好吧，我怎么绘制一个三角形，从概念上来说，你们可以说，好吧，我需要什么
you know, okay, how do I render a triangle, conceptually what you could say is, okay, well, what do I need for that
我首先需要设置一些上下文，但在Vulcan，你们必须设置大量的上下文
I need to first of all set up some kind of contexts, but right in Vulcan, you'd have to set up like a crazy amount of things
例如，像命令提示一样，你们知道渲染设备
such as like command cues, you know rendering devices
像逻辑设备、物理设备，它们的其他提示实例是什么
like logical devices, physical devices, what what is the rest of their cues instances
我甚至不记得所有的事情，但至少我记得你们在Vulcan需要设置的所有事情
I didn't even remember everything, but I kind of at least all the things you need to set up in Vulcan
你们需要设置很多东西，而我，你们知道，我可以加入我特别喜欢的
there's a lot of stuff you need to set up, whereas I'm, you know, I can join my particularly like
好吧，还有帧缓冲显然也在Vulcan
okay, frank, oh and frame buff is obviously in Vulcan as well
就像你们需要得到所有的交换链一样，需要设置交换链
like you need to get all the swap chain, you need to set up your swap chain
设置帧缓冲区，为每个缓冲区或交换链设置帧缓冲区
and set up frame buffers, frame buffers for each buffer in the swap chain
这有很多你们需要做的事情，但本质上可以归结为
lots of stuff you need to do, but essentially it comes down to
我设置了我的上下文和渲染帧缓冲区，对了，我上传了一个顶点缓冲区和一个索引缓冲区
I set up my context and my rendering frame buffer, right, I upload a vertex buffer with vertices, I upload an index buffer with indices
我上传了一个着色器，设置了视口，以及其他类型的渲染上下文，然后发出个DrawCall
I upload a shader, I set my viewport maybe, and other kind of rendering context things, and then I issue a DrawCall
很可能就是那样，对吧，我就是那么做的，很明显，Vulcan中的流程需要更多的代码
that's probably about it, right, that's what I do, and like obviously that process in Vulcan is gonna require a lot more code
但那可能是你们，那可能是你们在屏幕上实际渲染三角形所需的步骤
but that might be your kind of, that might be the steps that you need to actually render a triangle on the screen
那么考虑到那一点，你们有足够的时间去你们能看到的地方
so with that in mind, you kind of have enough to go on where you can see
我想我可以在Vulcan和OpenGL中都能做到这一点
I'm gonna I can make this work in both Vulcan and OpenGL
因为我知道我需要什么，我知道我的步骤，它们看起来会不同
because I know what I need, I know my steps and they're just gonna look different
但本质上我已经画出了这条线，我有一个顶点缓冲区类
but essentially I've drawn that line at, I have a vertex buffer class
那就是我的抽象结束的地方，对吧，所以在顶点缓冲区类中
that's where my abstraction ends, right, so inside that vertex buffer class
我将有一个顶点缓冲区类的不同实现，它适用于Vulcan和OpenGL，对吧
I'll have a different implementation of that vertex buffer class, which applies to Vulcan OpenGL for example, right
然后是将要公开的接口，比如我想创建一个顶点缓冲区，它应该是这么多字节，对吧
and then the api that will be exposed of things, like I want to create a vertex buffer, it should be this many bytes, right
应该是这种用法，所以无论是动态的还是静态的，我都希望能够上传一个部分
it should be this kind of usage, so like whether it's kind of dynamic or static things like that, I want to be able to upload a section
我希望能够映射缓冲区或将一段数据上载到缓冲区中的特定偏移量
I want to be able to maybe map the buffer or upload a section of data to a particular offset in the buffer
所以我希望接口可用，我希望能够看到缓冲区的大小，希望能够设置缓冲区的布局
so I want that api available, I want to be able to see the size of the buffer, want to be able to set the layout of the buffer
这样我们就知道如何使用它进行实际渲染，以及其中的数据是什么样子的，对吧
so that we know how to actually render with it, and what the data inside there looks like those kinds of things, right
我想绑定缓冲区，我想做很多事情，对吧，但关键是你们已经创建了一个接口
I want to bind the buff, I want lots of stuff to do, right, but the idea is you've created an api
所以那是我们需要做的第一件事，我们需要创建一个，我们需要创建一个渲染器接口
so that's really the first thing that we need to kind of do, we need to create a, we need to create a renderer api
现在没办法了，我想坐在这里，把每一个类和每一个细节都写下来
now there is no way, I want to sit down here, and write you everything every single class and every single detail right now
因为那将非常冗长，你们知道，就像设计一个完整的规范
because that'll be extremely lengthy, and you know, that's like designing a whole specification
我们会一直这样做，但正如我下次所说的，当我想为你们做一个小小的PPT时
we're gonna do it as we go along, but as I said next time, when I have like a little powerpoint presentation for you guys
那就是我要接受的可能来自评论的一些建议，以及在这方面有经验的人的建议
that's where I'm gonna take in probably some suggestions with the come from the comments, as well from people who are experienced in this
就像我看起来一样，我已经做了很多年了，很多年了，很明显，在专业方面也是如此
just because like I look, I've been doing this for years and years and years and years, and professionally as well obviously
我对想法非常开放，因为这类东西
and I'm more than open to ideas, because this kind of stuff
你们知道，有时我会突然学到一些新东西，我会想，哇，哇，我想重温这整件事
you know sometimes I'll learn something new suddenly, I'll be like whoa whoa I want to revisit this whole thing
现在我有了这些基本信息，所以我们设计了一个接口
and rewrite it from scratch, now that I have this basic information, right, anyway, so we designed an api
我们需要拿出一个接口，从本质上讲，在这里画出了抽象线，这样才能真正知道低级别
we need to come up with an api, essentially where we where we draw the line of abstraction, so that we actually know how kind of low level
顺便说一句，那通常是最终发生的事情，你们有一个渲染接口抽象层
that'll be usually what ends up happening by the way is that you have like kind of a, you have your render api abstraction layer
最重要的是，你们有一个渲染器，所以不喜欢渲染器不直接与任何渲染接口对接
and then on top of that, you have a Renderer, so you don't like the renderer does not directly interface with any rendering api
但你们仍然有那样的能力，对吧，所以渲染中继就是你们可能有场景图之类的东西的地方
but you still kind of have that, right, so the render relay is where you probably have things like your scene graph
你们知道任何批处理逻辑着色逻辑之类的东西
you know any kind of batching logic coloring logic that kind of stuff
那就是渲染器级别，对吧，嗯，还有渲染排序之类的东西
that's it like that renderer level, right, um and like render sorting and all of that kind of stuff
对吧，虽然你们知道，渲染器不处理渲染器接口的事情是像上传顶点缓冲区，上传纹理
right, whereas you know, the renderer ya doesn't deal with the renderer api is things like upload a vertex buffer, upload a texture
它本质上类似于渲染命令，但你们分散了它
it's like render commands essentially, but you've distracted it out
因此可以将渲染器接口切换到任何需要的位置
so that you can switch out the renderer api to whatever you want
好了，所以那就是我们需要设计的接口，我们现在要讨论渲染器
okay, so that's the api that we need to design, we're going to talk about the renderer just yet
我们将只讨论渲染器接口抽象，那是我们需要做的一件事，我们将在下周讨论
we're just going to talk about that renderer api abstraction, that's one thing we need to do, and we'll talk about that next week
你们知道，我这里还有很多其他的东西，比如命令执行和多线程
you know, I've got a lot of other things here as well, you know, there are things like command exec and multi threading
我不是说渲染器多线程，我是说像游戏引擎多线程
and I don't mean renderer multi threading, I mean like game engine multi-threading
例如，从游戏线程或应用程序线程提交命令是非常常见的
so it's very common for example to actually submit commands from your game thread or from your application thread
但那只是命令的提交
but all that is is a command submission
所以你们看到，我想上传这个纹理，或者请在GPU上为我创建一个顶点缓冲区，对吧
so you see, I want to upload this texture, or please create a vertex buffer for me on the GPU, right
该代码的作用是获取exec，将其放入一个称为指令exec或类似于渲染指令exec的东西中
what happens with that code is it gets exec, it gets put into something called a command exec, or like a render command exec
然后发生的是渲染线程，当它启动时，它会遍历命令列表并执行它们
and then what happens is the render thread, when that starts up, it goes through the list of commands and executes them
好了，很多接口实际上都是这样做的，比如Vulcan和DirectX，在它们里面有这样的东西
okay, a lot of api actually do stuff like this, like Vulcan DirectX well for example have that stuff in them
但就像OpenGL没有那样，现在通常都是自己设计这些东西
but like OpenGL doesn't, so usually it's common nowadays to actually design that stuff yourself
我们可能得把它做好，我来教你们怎么做
we'll have to do that right probably, and I'll show you guys how to do that
因为它很，我不知道，它很酷，我很喜欢它，尽管它有时很乏味
because it's quite, I don't know, it's quite cool, I quite like it, even though it is sometimes tedious
但本质上，你们有一个类似的命令和代码，它可以复制命令所需的所有数据以及命令本身
but essentially you have like a command and code that goes through, and like it copies all the data you need for a command plus the command itself
加上一个函数指针，然后像二进制缓冲一样存储所有那些
plus maybe like a function pointer, and then you store all of that in like a binary buff
就像所有连续的内存一样，都是崩溃友好的，然后渲染线程就完成了
like it's all contiguous memories, that it's all kind of cash friendly, and then you kind of the render thread goes through that
这就像CPU读取CPU指令一样，就像不同的操作码一样
and like, it's almost like a cpu reading cpu instructions, where you go through it like different opcodes
你们看到，好了，我现在正在执行这个命令
and you see, okay, I'm doing this command now
代表你们知道，接下来的12个字节是以三个浮点形式的参数
the rep you know, the next 12 bytes are parameters in the form of three floats
所以像那样传输它们，这实际上很有趣，而且非常，你们可以使它非常有效，真的很酷
so transmit them like that, and it's actually quite interesting, and it's very, you can make it very efficient, which is really cool
因此，我们必须涵盖那样的内容，我们将讨论其中的一些缺点和优点
so we'll have to cover stuff like that, and we'll talk about some of the negatives of that as well as the positive
所以渲染有很多事情要做，我只是想让你们明白我有点不知所措
so there's a lot to do with rendering, I just want you guys to understand that I'm kind of overwhelmed
我想尽可能多地设计这个，我一直知道这会以某种方式发生
I want to design this as much as possible, I always knew this would happen in a way
但就像我一样，我们现在正在渲染的这个渲染几乎让人恼火
but like I just it's almost annoying that this rendering that we're up to rendering now
因为正如我所说的，我下个月就要结婚了
because as I said, I'm getting married next month
然后我要去度一段时间的蜜月，所以我会离开，这里会有视频
and then I'm gonna go on a honeymoon for a little bit of time, so I'll be away, and there will be videos here
很明显，我不想为渲染器架构和Hazel而担心，我应该要结婚了
and obviously I don't want to be warring about renderer architecture and Hazel, well I'm supposed to be getting married
所以正因如此，我想请你们在接下来的一两个月里对我放松，可能是五月中的两个月
so because of that, I'm just like asking you guys to just take it easy on me for the next month or two probably two months like in may
我应该百分之百地回来，但现在，我只是，我还是要试着每周发布一期视频
I should be back in action 100%, but like for now, I'm just, I'm gonna still try to release a video a week
但如果它不像你们想象的那么饱和，或者不如你们想象的那么好
but if it's like not as saturated, or not as good as you kind of
那么我们就没有你们想象的那么多
not as much we don't get as much done as you expect to
因为我只是想把这事说清楚
it's because I just kind of want to talk this through
我想确定我们有设计，因为这可能是Hazel最复杂的部分之一
I want to make sure we have a seller design, because this is probably one of the most complicated parts of Hazel
这绝对是最大的Hazel系统，我绝对想确保我们做到这一点，对吧
it's definitely the biggest system of Hazel, and I definitely want to just make sure that we get this kind of right
但你们也明白这一切的含义，因为这是一个教育系列
but also that you guys understand all the implications with this, because this is an educational series
我不是在为自己写Hazel，我们在一起做Hazel，我想让你们明白一切都是有效的
I'm not just writing Hazel for myself, we're building Hazel together, and I want you guys to understand everything works
无论如何，我想就那样吧，下次我们真正要做的是讨论渲染接口抽象
anyway, I think that's about it, next time what we're actually gonna do is talk about that rendering api abstraction
我要看看你们在评论中说了些什么，但我也要准备好那个PPT
I'm gonna see what you guys say in the comments, but also I'm going to get that power presentation ready
我们实际上讨论了如何将其抽象出来，将变成什么，以及一切将如何进行
where we actually talk about how we are going to abstract that, and what's going to turn into, and how everything's going to work
渲染器的整个体系结构实际上是我们下周要讨论的内容，而不是渲染器的体系结构
the whole architecture of the renderer is really what we're going to talk about to next week, and not really the architecture of the renderer
就像渲染接口抽象的架构，或者渲染接口、图形接口抽象，无论你们想怎么叫它
so much as the architecture of the render api abstraction, or the rendering api, graphics api abstraction, whatever you want to call it
好了，那就是下周，希望你们喜欢这期视频，我也需要在下周之前修复我的电脑
okay, so that's next week, hope you guys enjoyed this video, and I need to fix my computer before next week as well
所以这周不会是一个有趣的一周，不管怎样，我这周在EA工作室也有来自像frostbite的人
so this is not gonna be a fun week, anyway, now I've got people from like frostbite over in the EA studio this week as well
有太多事情发生了，我希望你们喜欢这个视频
there's so much stuff happening, I hope you guys enjoyed this video
如果你们喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧，可以通过patreon.com/thecherno来支持我
if you did, please hit that like button, you can help support me on patreon by going patreon.com/thecherno
我现在比以往任何时候都需要你们的支持，因为我就像
I need you guys support more than ever right now, because I'm just like just
我甚至想请无薪假期，因为这只是，一切都是压倒性的
I'm thinking of even taking like unpaid leave from work, because it's just, everything is just overwhelming
所以我想，你们知道，我真的很想继续为你们制作这些视频，因为我喜欢它，对吧，即使
so I would, you know, I really want to keep making these videos for you guys, because I love it, right, like even though
我现在可能有更重要的事情要做，我真的很喜欢为你们制作这些视频
there are potentially more important things for me to be doing right now, I really love making these videos for you guys
就像你们对我来说很重要，真的想为Hazel编写这个渲染器
like you mean a lot to me, and really do want to write this renderer for Hazel
和你们一起工作会很酷的
it's gonna be so cool, and working with you guys as well
那将是惊人的，所以如果你们能支持我，将可以访问很多源代码
and that is gonna be amazing, so if you can please support me, and you'll get access to a lot of this source code
我已经编写了，比如像渲染命令q，你们知道，就像在不同的线程上运行一样
I've already written like a render command q, you know, runs like on a different thread
我不认为它运行在不同的线程上，是的，但它是一种完整的命令处理器和命令q
I don't think it runs on a different thread, yeah but it is a full kind of command processor and command q
你们知道，可以提交命令的方式，我已经写了所有这些东西，它可以与OpenGL一起运行
you know, the way you can submit commands, I've already written all that stuff, and it works with OpenGL
我们正在接触的不仅仅是一个三角形，所有那些东西都在Hazel开发库中，已经准备好了
and we are entering more than just a triangle, all that stuff is in the Hazel development repository, already ready to go
所以，如果你们想向前看，看看这会是什么样子，一定要看看，我想我是
so if you want to kind of jump ahead and see kind of how this is going to look, definitely check that out, and I think that I am
因为那是OpenGL，我不确定具体在哪里，但我已经开始抽象了
because that is OpenGL, I'm not sure exactly where, but I am already beginning that abstraction
所以我在玩类似的东西，所以一定要看看，然后通常你们会提前一周收到视频
so I'm playing around with things like that, so definitely check that out, and then usually you'll get a videos a week early
我不能保证在接下来的两个月内，基本上在创作之前，你们每周都会很早收到视频
I can't promise for the next like two months, basically until made, you will get videos early every week
我会努力的，但就像我这周的意思一样，因为电脑的原因，我不能做那个
I'll try, but like I mean with this week, I kind of couldn't do that, because my computer
也许那样会更好，但你们的支持对我和这个系列来说意义重大，我告诉你们
maybe that'll be better, but again your support means a lot to me and this series, just I'm telling you like
因此，如果没有这些出色的支持者，它就不会在这里
so it would not be here without all those wonderful supporters
非常感谢你们，希望你们喜欢这期视频，下期见，拜
so thank you so much, hope you guys enjoy this video, I will see you next time, goodbye